<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Education on BernatBC</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/tags/education/</link><description>Recent content in Education on BernatBC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 06:00:23 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.bernatbc.tk/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VR Battlefield</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/vr-battlefield/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/vr-battlefield/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-statement">The statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We were asked to develop a Virtual Reality application using
&lt;a href="https://unity.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unity&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://arvr.google.com/cardboard/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Cardboard&lt;/a>. The app needed to have the following features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A virtual reality environment with various objects that can be interacted with.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigation: you can use either the reticle pointer provided by GoogleVR or the data entry from the mobile phone&amp;rsquo;s accelerometer, to move the camera within the environment virtual. You can implement any of the metaphors that we have seen in the classes of theory (constant movement, plane route selection, teleportation, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Selection: The user must have some 3DUI mode to be able to select objects from the scene, as well as being able to apply geometric transformations to perform tasks of manipulation (rotation, translation, scaling).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Control: Offer the user the possibility of doing some control task via 3D GUIs, for example example: modify the color of some object, load a model into the scene, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="what-weve-made">What we&amp;rsquo;ve made&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the video below you can take a look at the resulting app. To sum it up, we created a battleground environment where you can interact with several objects, such as grenades, mines and guns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3D Image Viewer</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/3dimageviewer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/3dimageviewer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This project was made for my bachelor thesis. You can take a look the full report
&lt;a href="https://upcommons.upc.edu/handle/2117/411671" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a> (note that&amp;rsquo;s in catalan).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since the arrival of the photographic camera, humans have seen the need to find a way to organize photographs. Nowadays, the ease and simplicity of taking a photograph causes large quantities of them to accumulate. The most popular photo viewers and galleries display one image after another, in a list or grid, making it difficult to organize and searching them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Object Tracker</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/objecttracker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/objecttracker/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-statement">The statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://amoudgl.github.io/tlp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Long-Term Visual Object Tracking Benchmark&lt;/a> is a dataset to benchmark object tracking algorithms. We were asked to implement four different algorithms. Two using tracking techniques, and two using recognition. For each technique, we had to implement one from scratch (an algorithm made for us) and another one extracted from the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given a series of frames and a bounding box corresponding to the object to track, the algorithm should follow the object. To evaluate the precision, we used the overlapping ratio between the computed bounding box and the optimal bounding box (which was given via a txt file).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>λ-Calculus Telegram Bot</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/lambdacalculustelegrambot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/lambdacalculustelegrambot/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-statement">The statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We were asked to make a lambda-calculus interpreter created by
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alonzo_Church" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alonzo Church&lt;/a>. This interpreter had also to support the definition and use of macros, a variable name for another expression. Those macros had to be evaluated in an infix (if it&amp;rsquo;s a symbol) or a prefix mode (otherwise). On top of that, our interpreter had to run in a
&lt;a href="https://telegram.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Telegram&lt;/a> chat. Finally, we had to add the capability to print our expression as a tree in an image.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Document manager</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/documentmanager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/documentmanager/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-statement">The statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Programming Projects&lt;/em> college subject asked us to create an application to manage documents using Java. This application has to feature the creation of a document, importing and exporting files in three different formats: plaintext, XML and our own format. The application also has to have the ability to delete and modify these documents. The main feature of the application is the various document queries that allow us to find a certain document or author in the application.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Planification project</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/planification/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/planification/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-statement">The statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are in the year 2075 and the first colonizers of Mars have established a network of bases throughout the geography of the planet that can be of two types, settlements (where the settlers live) and warehouses (where supplies arrive from the Earth). Moving between these bases is done by rovers that can move supplies and specialized personnel. It is not possible to always go directly from one base to another, we have a map (connected graph) that tells us which movements are possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Knowledge Based Systems</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/knowledgebasedsystems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/knowledgebasedsystems/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-statement">The statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The progressive aging of the population is showing the importance of maintaining a set of healthy habits and promote physical exercise throughout life. When you reach a certain age it is necessary to have help to determine what types of exercises and activities are the most appropriate taking into account all factors that may affect the performance of those activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, we had to make a
&lt;a href="https://clipsrules.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CLIPS&lt;/a> script that after given certain information about a person, we had to output an exercise planning suitable for him/her. We were given a bunch of documents about exercises for elder people where we had to extract the information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Local Search</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/localsearch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/education/localsearch/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-statement">The statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Given a set of Power plants and Clients, find an assignation for each Client where the total benefit is the maximum. Each power plant is represented by coordinates in a map, the total production and the cost when it&amp;rsquo;s stopped and running. Each client is represented by coordinates in a map, the power consumed, the price it pays for each Mw and a compensation in the case he doesn&amp;rsquo;t get power. Also, power gets drained if the distance between a power plant and a client is farther than a certain value.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>