<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Videogame on BernatBC</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/tags/videogame/</link><description>Recent content in Videogame on BernatBC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 06:00:22 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.bernatbc.tk/tags/videogame/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monopoly</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/videogames/monopoly/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 06:00:22 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/videogames/monopoly/</guid><description>The project After making the Minesweeper, I wanted to create something more elaborated. I decided to make a clone of Monopoly. Almost everybody has played at least one time to Monopoly, so I don&amp;rsquo;t need to make an introduction.
How it works I started with the player movement and the dice. When everything was smooth and playable, I started to make the cards. One thing I like about them is the fact that they aren&amp;rsquo;t images.</description></item><item><title>Minesweeper</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/videogames/minesweeper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/videogames/minesweeper/</guid><description>The project Before making this project, I&amp;rsquo;d used Unity game engine for making a couple of games like Tetris by following some Youtube tutorials. Also, I made Space Shooter during HackUPC2021, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t on my own. Now I wanted to do a project on my own and decided to start with a simple game. Minesweeper was a good candidate as it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem too complex. I didn&amp;rsquo;t reinvent the wheel and made a clone of minesweeper.</description></item><item><title>HackUPC 2021</title><link>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/competitions/hackupc2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.bernatbc.tk/posts/competitions/hackupc2021/</guid><description>About HackUPC HackUPC is the first student hackathon in Spain. Once a year, we aim to provide a space for students of all experience levels from all around the world where they can improve and learn new skills, meet awesome people, and overall have a great experience! This year&amp;rsquo;s edition will be held in a hybrid format, meaning that you can come in person but also participate from home.
Our project @miquelt9, @JCasahuga and I decided to participate in this hackathon in the first year of the degree.</description></item></channel></rss>