<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C++ on BernatBC</title><link>https://bernatbc.tk/tags/c++/</link><description>Recent content in C++ on BernatBC</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 06:00:23 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bernatbc.tk/tags/c++/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nordic Collegiate Programming Contest 2023</title><link>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/ncpc2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/ncpc2023/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-ncpc-2023">About NCPC 2023&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://nordic.icpc.io/ncpc2023/">Nordic Collegiate Programming Contest (NCPC)&lt;/a> is an annual team-based programming competition aimed at university and college students from the Nordic and Baltic countries. NCPC is suitable for programmers of all skill levels, from beginner to expert. The contest features a well-rounded problem set with a mix of easy and challenging problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Teams are allowed only one computer, and are not allowed to surf through the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="problems-solved">Problems Solved&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="problem-c-converting-romans">Problem C: Converting Romans&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ncpc23.kattis.com/contests/ncpc23/problems/convertingromans">Statement of Problem C: Converting Romans&lt;/a>
&lt;br />
Once I read this problem, I directly went to code it in the computer as it seemed easy. I coded the usual roman to decimal converter, but then I noticed that they asked for a simpler version of the problem: &amp;ldquo;we will subtract any digit written to the left of a larger digit, even if they are not directly adjacent.&amp;rdquo; making the problem easier. I had a couple of little issues with the slight modification of the problem, but eventually I managed to solve it. This was the first problem we managed to get it right.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vintè Concurs de Programació de la UPC - Semifinal 2022</title><link>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/20concursupc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/20concursupc/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-the-contest">About the contest&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Each year, &lt;a href="https://fme.upc.edu/en">School of Mathematics and Statistics&lt;/a> from &lt;a href="https://www.upc.edu/en?set_language=en">Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya&lt;/a> organizes a coding competition for all students enrolled to &lt;a href="https://www.upc.edu/en?set_language=en">UPC&lt;/a>. During 4 hours, the contestants try to solve as many coding problems as possible. A rank is made considering the number of solved problems and penalization points. For each wrong submission, they add 20 minutes to the total of time used for each solved problem. So the sooner you solve them, the better.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Hash Code 2022</title><link>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/hashcode2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/hashcode2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-google-hash-code">About Google Hash Code&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://codingcompetitions.withgoogle.com/hashcode">Google Hash Code&lt;/a> is a team programming competition, organized by Google, for students and professionals around the world. It allows you to share your skills and connect with other coders as you work together to solve a problem modeled off a real Google engineering challenge! In small teams of two to four, coders all over the world will tackle the first problem through Qualification Round. Though this round is hosted online, teams can come together virtually to compete side-by-side in locally coordinated Hash Code Hubs. The top teams from this round are invited to join us for the virtual World Finals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Code Jam 2021</title><link>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/codejam2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/codejam2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-google-code-jam">About Google Code Jam&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Google’s longest running global coding competition, &lt;a href="https://codingcompetitions.withgoogle.com/codejam">Google Code Jam&lt;/a>, calls on programmers around the world to solve challenging, algorithmic puzzles against the clock. Contestants advance through four online-hosted rounds to compete at the annual Code Jam World Finals that is held at a different international Google office each year. Each round brings new challenges, and in the end 25 contestants will have the ultimate chance to put their skills to the test, vying for cash prizes and the coveted championship title at the World Finals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Hash Code 2021</title><link>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/hashcode2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://bernatbc.tk/posts/contests/hashcode2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-google-hash-code">About Google Hash Code&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://codingcompetitions.withgoogle.com/hashcode">Google Hash Code&lt;/a> is a team programming competition, organized by Google, for students and professionals around the world. It allows you to share your skills and connect with other coders as you work together to solve a problem modeled off a real Google engineering challenge! In small teams of two to four, coders all over the world will tackle the first problem through Qualification Round. Though this round is hosted online, teams can come together virtually to compete side-by-side in locally coordinated Hash Code Hubs. The top teams from this round are invited to join us for the virtual World Finals.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>